HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGER/OPERATIONS ADMINISTRATOR

Summary

Employee Relations Project Management Organizational Development Employee Recruitment ISO 9001 Experience Customer Service SAP Experience Microsoft Office Suite PeopleSoft ADP and Ceridian Accounting System Executive level professional who has nearly fifteen years of work experience and an expertise in Human Resource Management. Successful employee liaison and program administrator. Plays an integral role within an organization by providing collaboration, motivation and direction across teams in diverse environments. Highlights

benefits, database management, database, delivery, financial, hiring, Human Resources, insurance, ISO 9001, legal, managing, Materials, Works, negotiating, new product development, optimization, payroll, PeopleSoft, policies, pricing, processes, Purchasing, quality, Express, SAP/R3, supervisor, strong analytical background

Accomplishments

- Staffing and recruiting professional, Written job descriptions, procedures, and policies
- Benefits administrator Performance management strategies
- Employee relations, FMLA, ADA, FLSA
- Manager coaching and training, Workers' Comp experience
- Revamped the orientation process for all new hires, which was implemented company-wide
- Served as key contributing member to Leadership team
- Develop and Implement an appropriate employee compensation structure using pay grades, employee titles, background, employment history, market analysis.
- Confidentiality
- Provides support for the recruiting offices and keeping an database of timekeeping, job tasks, and conduct.
- Run query reports in SAP on employee history, titles, personal, and professional
- C onducting job evaluations analysis
- Conducting market research analysis

Experience

Five Star Quality Care, Inc. February 2013 to Current Human Resource Manager/Operations Administrator Topeka, KS

Duties include management of employee hiring process including posting available positions, review and distribution of resumes, coordination of interview process, preparation of compensation packages and planning new hire orientation process. Responsible for managing the employee evaluation and training processes along with employee termination activities. Works in partnership with the legal department to revised internal policies and procedures when necessary due to new or changing legislature. Direct supervisor for all temporary employees. Responsible for the preparation of ISO 9001 Audit. Basic knowledge of state and federal regulatory compliance: HIPAA, COBRA, FMLA, ADA, Workers' Compensation and Short-term disability.

Kerry Ingredients And Flavours November 2012 to February 2013 Human Resources Coordinator

Nixa, MO Human Resources Coordinator at Kings Mountain International for Ultra Force Services. Duties include time-keeping of employees. Responsible for managing and tracking invoices. Answering inbound and outbound calls to resolve unforeseen issues. Maintaining the introduction of new program while implementing the new changes to employees.

GAMCO April 2011 to October 2012 Buyer

City, STATE Materials Buyer at Gamco Services for Express Pros Services. Duties included negotiating pricing and delivery terms with suppliers and processing material orders in SAP/R3. Coordinated order expediting activities when necessary.

EXPRESS PROS October 2009 to April 2011 Supply Chain Management/HR Associate

City, STATE Duties included acting as lead contact person to assist employees with issues related to payroll, insurance, Family Medical Leave Act and various employee benefits such as maternity or medical leave process. Kings Mountain, NC Supply Chain Management/HR Associate 02/2007 to 03/2008 Contract Job with Express Pros at Colortex in Gastonia, NC. Duties included customer order placement and tracking along with database management activities. Tracking invoices and answering inbound and outbound calls.

WELLS FARGO May 2005 to January 2006 Credit Card Service Manager

City, STATE Duties included resolving financial issues from call in customers and referring account optimization services to customers. STABILUS August 1998 to August 2005 Engineering Business Analyst/Executive Assistant

City, STATE Stabilus in Gastonia, NC. Duties included managing a material part number harmonization project across two manufacturing locations and functioned as the departmental internal auditor for a variety of quality of certification programs such as ISO 9001. Also worked with the Purchasing department to ensure accurate order placement for parts needed for new product development.

Education

Gardner Webb University 2006 MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION: HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT City, State, US MASTER OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION: HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT 2006 Gardner Webb University, Boiling Springs, NC Human Resource Management

Belmont Abbey University 2002 BACHELOR OF ARTS: BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION City, State, US BACHELOR OF ARTS: BUSINESS ADMINISTRATIO 2002 Belmont Abbey University, Belmont, NC Business Administration Skills

Iso, Buying/procurement, Executive Assistant, Product Development, Purchasing, Transmissions, Ada, Audit, Cobra, Compensation, Disability, Fmla, Hipaa, New Hire Orientation, Operations, Posting, Regulatory Compliance, Short-term Disability, Training, Human Resources, Buyer, Pricing, R3, Sap, Benefits, Employee Benefits, Payroll, Answering, Inbound And Outbound, Invoices, Outbound Calls, Associate, Database,

Database Management, Hr, Peoplesoft, Supply Chain, Supply Chain Management, Credit, Credit Card, Optimization, Accounting, Adp, Ceridian, Coaching, Customer Service, Employee Relations, Liaison, Microsoft Office, Ms Office, New Hires, New Product Development, Org Development, Organizational Development, Performance Management, Project Management, Receptionist, Recruiting, Recruitment, Retail Sales, Staffing, Human Resource Management